<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class
	name="IcyAudioDecoder"
	inherits="RefCounted"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd"
>
	<brief_description>
		Generic audio decoder class providing a common interface for audio stream decoders with buffering support.
	</brief_description>

	<description>
		[IcyAudioDecoder] is a generic audio decoder base class that provides a common interface for audio stream decoders.
		It manages interaction with an [AudioStreamGeneratorPlayback] instance and provides a standardized buffering mechanism, including configurable buffer thresholds, buffering state tracking, and notifications when buffering starts or finishes.

		[b]Note:[/b] Derived classes are expected to implement the actual decoding logic.
	</description>

	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>

	<signals>
		<signal name="buffering_started">
			<description>
				Emitted when the buffered audio data has been depleted and the decoder enters the buffering state.
			</description>
		</signal>

		<signal name="buffering_finished">
			<description>
				Emitted when the buffered audio data reaches the configured target threshold and buffering completes.
			</description>
		</signal>
	</signals>

	<methods>
		<method name="set_playback">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="playback" type="AudioStreamGeneratorPlayback" />
			<description>
				Sets the [AudioStreamGeneratorPlayback] instance used by the decoder for buffer management. This playback object is used to determine the current buffering state and available audio frames.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="set_buffer_thresholds">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="target_frames" type="int" />
			<param index="1" name="max_capacity_frames" type="int" />
			<description>
				Configures the buffering thresholds used by the decoder.
				[code]target_frames[/code] specifies the number of buffered frames required before buffering is considered complete, while [code]max_capacity_frames[/code] specifies the maximum expected buffer capacity.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="process_audio">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Processes decoder-specific audio handling and moves raw audio frame data into the [AudioStreamGeneratorPlayback]'s ring buffer.
				[b]Note:[/b] This method is intended to be implemented by derived decoder classes.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="get_buffering_progress" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the current buffering progress as a value between [code]0.0[/code] and [code]1.0[/code].
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="is_buffering" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the decoder is currently buffering audio data, otherwise returns [code]false[/code].
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="get_current_target_frames" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns the current target number of buffered frames required before playback can resume after buffering.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="get_current_max_capacity_frames" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns the configured maximum buffer capacity, expressed in audio frames.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
