<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class
	name="IcyHttpStream"
	inherits="RefCounted"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd"
>
	<brief_description>
		Handles HTTP requests and continuous audio streaming from Icecast servers.
	</brief_description>

	<description>
		[IcyHttpStream] establishes HTTP connections to Icecast-compatible servers and continuously downloads streaming audio data on a dedicated thread.
		If an AudioDecoder is assigned, downloaded data chunks are forwarded to it for decoding. Otherwise, the stream remains active and incoming data is discarded.
		The class can optionally parse ICY metadata embedded in the stream and emits signals for connection state changes and metadata updates.
	</description>

	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>

	<signals>
		<signal name="connection_opened">
			<description>
				Emitted when a connection to the streaming server has been successfully established and data reception begins.
			</description>
		</signal>

		<signal name="connection_closed">
			<description>
				Emitted when the connection is closed, either intentionally or due to an error. [param result] contains a [enum Result] value describing the reason the connection was closed.
			</description>
		</signal>

		<signal name="metadata_received">
			<description>
				Emitted when ICY metadata is received from the server. The format and contents of [param metadata] depend on the metadata provided by the stream.
			</description>
		</signal>
	</signals>

	<methods>
		<method name="request">
			<return type="void" />

			<param index="0" name="url" type="String" />
			<param index="1" name="timeout" type="float" default="5.0" />
			<param index="2" name="parse_metadata" type="bool" default="false" />
			<param
				index="3"
				name="custom_headers"
				type="PackedStringArray"
				default="PackedStringArray()"
			/>

			<description>
				Sends an HTTP GET request to [param url] and attempts to establish a streaming connection.
				If the connection succeeds, the stream begins downloading data continuously on a dedicated thread until the connection is closed or interrupted.
				[param url] specifies the URL of the Icecast stream.
				[param timeout] specifies the connection timeout in seconds.
				If [param parse_metadata] is [code]true[/code], ICY metadata embedded in the stream is parsed and exposed through the appropriate signals.
				[param custom_headers] specifies additional HTTP headers to include in the request such as user agent or bearer token. Each entry must be formatted as [code]"Header-Name: Value"[/code].
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="cancel_request">
			<return type="void" />

			<description>
				Cancels the active request or stream, if one exists.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="is_requesting">
			<return type="void" />

			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if a request is currently active or data is being streamed.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="get_content_mime_type">
			<return type="String" />

			<description>
				Returns the MIME type of the streamed media. (e.g [code]"audio/mpeg"[/code] for MP3 streams)
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="get_response_headers">
			<return type="PackedStringArray" />

			<description>
				Returns the raw HTTP response headers.
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="get_response_headers_as_dictionary">
			<return type="Dictionary" />

			<description>
				Returns the HTTP response headers as a key-value [Dictionary].
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
